Guide to the Committees of Yale University Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Committees of Yale University records
1889-1999
RU 153
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.5
The records consist of correspondence, reports, minutes, drawings, and subscription lists documenting the activities of Yale committees, such as the Lecture Committee, Committee on University Publications, Committee on Memorials, and the Committee on Faculty Appointments.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 6 (YRG 6), Records of Yale committees.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, reports, minutes, drawings, and subscription lists documenting the activities of Yale committees, such as the Lecture Committee, Committee on University Publications, Committee on Memorials, and the Committee on Faculty Appointments.
Committees; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale University -- Administration
- Committee on the deanship and the study of the administrative organization of the School of Medicine, 1945; Accession 19ND-A-469
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Records of the Committee on the deanship and the study of the administrative organization of the School of Medicine, 1945 (Box 1)
- Various committee reports and records, 1889-1918; Accession 1937-A-003
  - Committee on Examination for Degrees, report, undated (Box 1)
  - Nominating Committee on a Memorial for President Woolsey, records, 1889-1890 (Box 1)
  - Committee on Dodge, Bromley, and Woodward Lectures, minutes, 1910-1913 (Box 1)
  - Committee on Memorials, Records, 1916-1918 (Box 1)
  - Committee on University Publications report, 1906 (Box 1)
  - Committee on the Civil War Memorial, minutes of meetings, 1909-1915 (Box 1)
- Committee reports and response to the report of the ad hoc Committee on Faculty Appointments, 1980-1992; Accession 1994-A-105
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2027
  - Response by Donald Kagan to the Report of the ad hoc Committee on Faculty Appointments, James Tobin, chair, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Report of the Managerial and Professional Committee to the Office of the University, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Report of the Faculty of Arts and Sciences review Committee, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- NEASC Reaccreditation Self-Study Steering Committee report, "Yale University: Institutional Self-Study", 1999; Accession 2002-A-018
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2035
  - NEASC Reaccreditation Self-Study Steering Committee report, "Yale University: Institutional Self-Study", 1999 (Box 1)
- Assorted committee minute books, circa 1927-1972; Accession 2003-A-018
  - Committee on Award of Undergraduate Scholarships, 1938-1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Bursary Appointments
    - 1932-1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1945-1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Financial Aids Committee, 1956-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Governing Board of the Dept. of Personnel Study and Bureau of Appointments
    - 1927-1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1937-1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)